# **Gregory Hewett**

https://www.linkedin.com/in/ghewett

## **Summary**

Full stack software engineer with experience building, scaling, and maintaining highly reliable web applications. I am deeply analytical, enjoy investigating and solving hard problems, and prefer to work on something that challenges me. I thrive when designing and building features that users love and appreciate working with lots of people and across teams.

## **Education**

#### Harvard University | Cambridge, MA

Class of 2017

[Degree] Joint AB in Computer Science & Electrical Engineering. GPA: 3.7/4.0. Coursework in computer science, engineering, design, innovation, entrepreneurship, writing, physics, and more.

[Senior Thesis Project] EpiFib: Creating a Network of Life-Saving Medical Devices

- Mobile app and IoT network for finding EpiPens and heart defibrillators in emergencies.
- App allows users to find and alert people nearby who can quickly provide an EpiPen.

## Relevant Experience

#### Evocalize | Seattle, WA

Summer 2020 - Present

[Senior Software Engineer] Full stack software engineer building the foundation of Evocalize: a collaborative marketing platform that simplifies and automates digital marketing execution.

- Designed, built, and maintained GraphQL and REST APIs in Kotlin and Spring Boot with PostgreSQL
- Created product specs and led implementation for several features across frontend and backend teams
- Led planning and implementation of a self-service onboarding portal to improve customer onboarding speed
- Developed backend infrastructure to add Google Search ads and metrics into the Evocalize platform
- Created partner-facing APIs for managing and creating custom content to power ads
- Mentored junior engineers and promoted a culture of engineering excellence

#### Microsoft - Bing | Bellevue, WA

**Summer 2017 - Summer 2020** 

[Software Engineer II] Full stack software engineer working on Microsoft Search: a high-performing search experience across Microsoft cloud products including Bing, Office.com, SharePoint, and Windows.

- Built and maintained core backend API components to power the enterprise search experience
- Developed frontend infrastructure and UX components for a full-page revamp of the entire UI
- Developed a high throughput, low latency, and highly relevant people search/auto-suggest/auto-complete experience
- Implemented authentication protocols and enterprise identity management in Bing.com
- Mentored engineers and promoted highly scalable and efficient coding practices
- Led communication and planning for key features across organizations and teams
- Found and fixed numerous live site impacting bugs, including an obscure .NET memory leak and TCP connection issue
- Met with customers on a regular basis to help debug issues and get feedback

### The Reach Lab | Cambridge, MA

**Spring 2015 - Winter 2017** 

[Founder and CEO] Founded The Reach Lab, LLC and designed, developed, and created The Reach Lab mobile app that helps people and professionals stay in touch. iOS app coded in Swift. No longer maintained.

# **Additional Experience**

#### Harvard School of Engineering and Applied Sciences | Cambridge, MA

**Spring 2015 - Summer 2017** 

[Teaching Fellow] Taught material and ran engineering labs for the introductory Electrical Engineering class, and, previously, the introductory Mechanical Engineering class. 12 hours/week.

#### Harvard College High-Tech and Business Group | Cambridge, MA

Fall 2014

[Co-President] Led a group of students interested in the intersection of technology and business and organized events to help educate students about Big Data, startups, and other prominent technology spaces.

### **Skills and Interests**

- C#/.NET, Kotlin, GraphQL, PostgreSQL, React, Redux, JavaScript/TypeScript, HTML, CSS/SCSS/LESS, GIT, MSTest
- Distributed systems, security, multi-threaded design, No-SQL databases, search, marketing, debugging, problem solving, compliance, and live site operations